In this video, we're going to talk about
sub account segments and accounts in
Dynamics SL and then look at how that
information can be used in Business
Central.
An organization's chart of accounts is
made up of a list of natural accounts,
sometimes called main accounts.
Most companies want to be able to
analyze transactions that are posted to
their natural accounts.
Categorizing transactions can help to
better understand a company's expenses
and revenues,
primarily their profit and loss
accounts.
Companies may want to categorize revenue
by region and market segments and
expenses by department and projects.
This can be done through the use of sub
accounts in Dynamics SL.
First, let's go to the sub account
maintenance screen in SL to see the sub
accounts that have been defined.
There can be up to eight sub account
segments defined in the flex key
definition screen in Dynamics SL.
The main account and sub account
combinations are used to report and
record on financial data.
In this example, the sub account is
broken into six different segments,
including reporting unit, company
segment, location, group, and sales type
and region.
Each have a specific position and length
in the format.
Next, let's look at the segment and what
the values are for those segments.
If I select a segment, I can then click
on the look up to see all the various
values that I've set up in my
organization.
Now, let's look at how the main account
and segments can be migrated in Business
Central.
In the SL company migration
configuration tool, you can include
which segments you would like to be
global dimensions.
Similar to segments, dimensions in
Business Central let you categorize and
analyze transactions posted to the chart
of accounts
instead of creating separate ledger
accounts for each division or
department. Dimensions can be used in
combination with your main account to
analyze information and reduce the need
for a large and complex chart of
accounts.
Business Central has two global
dimensions. These should be the most
common segments as you easily sort and
filter on these dimensions.
The remainder of your segments will be
migrated as shortcut dimensions.
In Business Central, let's see where
those global and shortcut dimensions are
defined.
To navigate to the general ledger setup,
we will select the search icon and enter
general ledger setup and choose that
from the search results.
In the setup window, we can see that the
reporting unit and company segment has
been set up as global dimensions.
If I had more than those segments in SL,
the remaining segments would come over
as shortcut dimensions in Business
Central.
Next, let's navigate to the dimension
window where you can see the existing
dimensions and create new ones later on
should you want to start analyzing
additional information in Business
Central.
If I select my reporting unit dimension
and go to dimension values, I can see
all of my segment values.
I could also create additional ones in
the future.
Finally, let's see how the chart of
accounts looks in Business Central.
In my chart of accounts, all of the main
accounts as defined in SL can be
migrated to Business Central and I can
see all of my balances for each account.
If I want to drill back on the balances,
I can see all of my reporting unit and
company segments with the amounts broken
out for each.
Similar to how it looks in Dynamics SL.
That's a quick look at segments and
dimensions in Dynamics SL and Business
Central.
To learn more about Business Central,
see the following resources.